<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="4.0.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-01-04T17:15:42-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Victor J Perez III</title><subtitle>Write an awesome description for your new site here. You can edit this line in _config.yml. It will appear in your document head meta (for Google search results) and in your feed.xml site description.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Being As If</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Being-As-If.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Being As If" /><published>2019-11-12T04:59:50-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:59:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Being-As-If</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Being-As-If.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, there are two distinct versions of myself separated by mind and body. As far as the mind is concerned we have Victor II, the current rendition that exists today, and then the Victor that looked into the mirror nine years ago: Victor I. Victor I, birthed of shame and anxiety, exists as a foil to the pride and perfectionism of Victor II. They represent themselves with fear and insecurity, dysmorphia and dysphoria. I’ve lost many years of my life to them, passed over many opportunities. My memories of living as &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; are hazy unclear, and suppressed. In some ways, parts of &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; remain inside of me. Upon looking into a mirror, I sometimes see the body of Victor II through the mind of &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt;, not recognizing my form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The body of Victor II and &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; is only separated by a severe class III jaw malocclusion– an underbite. &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; is an anomaly and a deformity: their physical form slowly birthed a mind, quickly replacing the original. After years of existing as them, I was given a promise of freedom from the metaphorical chains of &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt;. All I needed to do was wear a set of literal chains, and undergo an allegedly transformative surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make no mistake, the mind of &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; was not killed by that surgery. By that point, they were barely alive, waiting to be dropped into the void. Their death and Victor II’s rebirth came when I decided that my pursuit of physical perfection was only leading me down a road of eternal patience. So I acted as if my flesh machine was in the form of my post-surgery self. It took many years of work to beat back the tumorous growth that was &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There will come a time that I will not think of this distinction between Victors anymore, as the distinction will no longer exist. The mind of Victor II slowly becomes accustomed to their body again and thus will bring forth the demise of both. For now, I will just continue with this confusing existence.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here In my mind, there are two distinct versions of myself separated by mind and body. As far as the mind is concerned we have Victor II, the current rendition that exists today, and then the Victor that looked into the mirror nine years ago: Victor I. Victor I, birthed of shame and anxiety, exists as a foil to the pride and perfectionism of Victor II. They represent themselves with fear and insecurity, dysmorphia and dysphoria. I’ve lost many years of my life to them, passed over many opportunities. My memories of living as Victor I are hazy unclear, and suppressed. In some ways, parts of Victor I remain inside of me. Upon looking into a mirror, I sometimes see the body of Victor II through the mind of Victor I, not recognizing my form.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/beingasif.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/beingasif.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Running For Buckthorn</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Running-For-Buckthorn.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Running For Buckthorn" /><published>2019-11-12T04:50:54-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:50:54-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Running-For-Buckthorn</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Running-For-Buckthorn.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was originally published February 19th, 2018 and was re-published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I feel like I’ve been running my whole life. I’ve run figuratively from many things. Trying to avoid my problems, hoping they would go away. That’s how I ended up in Morgantown, after all. The first time I ran away from home was at the greatest place on earth; Disney World. I was never a very calm child. What I craved most was excitement and thrills. My parents just wanted to take a nice picture in front of the flowers. Pictures ran very antithetical to what I craved as a child. They made me mad, and I loudly rebelled whenever they were taken. “Where are the roller coasters? I wanna ride the roller coasters,” I can imagine myself demanding loudly. Finally, I snapped. We were at a photo studio for all the Disney characters waiting in line to take a picture with Goofy. Can you imagine waiting in line for something that wasn’t a roller coaster? I was having none of that nonsense. My mother said something very poorly thought out in the moment: “If you don’t like it, you can just leave.” So I did. Eight year old me left his family and started wandering around in Epcot, one of the few Disney World parks without roller coasters, to find a roller coaster. Yet, I was a determined little child, and relentless in my unknowingly pointless search.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After around thirty minutes of limitless freedom, I saw a horri- fying sight: my aunt in a full speed sprint, high heels in hand. I tried running, but it was too late. She tackled me with full force, and started hitting and yelling at me for leaving and worrying my family. I don’t know what felt worse: the fact that all that running had been for nothing, or the high heels.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III - I</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was originally published February 19th, 2018 and was re-published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here Running from friends. Running from life. Running from family. No matter where I go, I can’t escape. Running from anxiety. Running from reality. Running from my future career. I’ve never been much of an athlete. My legs and my lungs are always in competition of what will give first. Running from my desires, because I felt like I was never worth them. Running from my needs, because other peoples’ were more important. Running is pointless and exhausting. Trying to justify why you’re running is almost as bad as the act of running itself.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/bands.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/bands.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Mouth Mantra</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Mouth-Mantra.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mouth Mantra" /><published>2019-11-12T04:50:50-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:50:50-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Mouth-Mantra</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Mouth-Mantra.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ My mouth was sewn up ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Upon waking up from my surgery, The first thing I noticed was how much I didn’t feel. Everything was numb and bloated. Uncomfortable, but not painful. The second thing I noticed was that I could not open my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt;. Strong elastic bands were attached to the surgical hooks on my braces. The only thing that could force my teeth apart was the strong convulsions that came with me vomiting blood all over myself while resting on my hospital bed. My lips were swollen as if my surgeon bundled in a botox injection with my double &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; surgery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ I have followed a path | That took sacrifices ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the promised surgery. The one event that would change my life, solve all my problems. The surgery that five years of braces led up to. After being delayed three times, it was finally done. I always felt uncomfortable with the idea that one expensive medical procedure could fix all of your problems. Life is never that simple. Looking back though, it wasn’t just one medical procedure, it was years of sacrifice. Vacations abandoned for dental appointments. Internships forsaken for delayed surgery dates. So much pain. All leading up to eight of surgery, and three months of recovery.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My surgery was successful without any complications whatsoever. They didn’t even have to insert the dreaded catheter. All that was left was to heal. Two weeks in, my swelling went down enough to start moving my lips: I could speak. It took effort to make out the words, but I could communicate. Sometime after, a release show for the publication I worked hard on for a year took place. I was in a different state: another sacrifice I had to make for my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt;. Then, as I was about to sleep, I received a message from a friend about how much my work meant to him, and how he wished I was there to see the show. Over a hundred people showed up to that event, and I was not one of them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ Remove this hindrance ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There’s a reason double &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; surgery is considered a medical procedure and not a cosmetic procedure. The position of my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; prevented me from breathing easily through my nose, which meant I ended up breathing through my mouth most of the time. This led to an increase in cavities as well as gingivitis. Since my underbite was severe, I couldn’t eat with my front teeth, which meant the back teeth wore down faster than my others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;None of those medical issues concerned me. The blight of my underbite was the social anxieties I dealt with because of it. I was a sloppy eater, especially when it came to sandwiches, so I hated eating in front of other people. It was difficult for me to smile. As if I was permanently in a bad mood, I wore a frown wherever I went. When it came to talking, I spoke as sloppily as I ate. Words would be mumbled and jumbled together, and occasionally spit and drool would leave my mouth. Most of all, I felt ugly. I would look in the mirror and see a flesh shoe poking out from the bottom of my head.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For years, I refused to form close relationships with anyone for any reason. I only wanted one thing; that life-changing surgery that was dangling in front of my eyes. My mother would often say: “Once you get your jaw fixed, you won’t be able to stop smiling!” I resent her for saying that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ I was separated | From what I can do ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After nearly three weeks of recovering in Virginia, it was time to go back to Morgantown. I no longer had to eat with a syringe, and the swelling went down enough to make my speech more fluid. I was welcomed by my close friends, who understood me enough to make conversation. It was tiring, but I was able to live in relative normalcy for the next two weeks that my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; would be closed shut. Unfortunately, the liquid diet I was on eventually proved things difficult.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Walking to and from class while barely ingesting a thousand calories a day meant I was faced with rapid weight loss. I would meet with close friends and talk for a while, but it left my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; sore and my body exhausted for the rest of the day. One week after moving in, I looked down at my belt and noticed that it was two positions tighter than I usually put it. My weight was dropping, and I couldn’t eat enough to make up for it. But this was just another sacrifice, one of the last few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ Need to break up | Vicious habits ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Three years ago, I grew impatient. I had waited so long for the life-altering event, that it no longer seemed achievable. It had already been delayed once after all. So I resolved to remove the heartless parasite birthed from my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt;. To anyone that would listen, I would force myself to speak to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And then my surgery was delayed again. My morale was crushed, and I began to assess my progress. I had surrounded myself with the first people willing to be my friend, however, I came to understand that not all friends are good. So I started over, and at the suggestion of someone I casually spoke to at a birthday party, I joined my college’s radio station. I started making real friends, ones I could depend on. The years passed, and eventually, I realized that the only time people recognized my underbite was when I stuck my finger in between the gap that formed when my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; was closed. When the third delay came, it didn’t bring as much despair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;“ With jaw fallen in | In fallen jaw ”&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In five days from the time I’m writing this, the elastics holding my jaw together will be removed. I will be able to talk and breathe easier, but I will still be unable to eat solid food for two weeks more. Six weeks with a closed &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; is a small sacrifice for such a life-changing surgery. I do wonder though, why haven’t I felt self concious about my mouth being clamped shut? Why am I so calm? Did my surgery really cause this?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III - II</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here “ My mouth was sewn up ” Upon waking up from my surgery, The first thing I noticed was how much I didn’t feel. Everything was numb and bloated. Uncomfortable, but not painful. The second thing I noticed was that I could not open my jaw. Strong elastic bands were attached to the surgical hooks on my braces. The only thing that could force my teeth apart was the strong convulsions that came with me vomiting blood all over myself while resting on my hospital bed. My lips were swollen as if my surgeon bundled in a botox injection with my double jaw surgery.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/jaw.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/jaw.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Sisyphus</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/music/2019/11/12/Sisyphus.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Sisyphus" /><published>2019-11-12T04:50:47-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:50:47-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/music/2019/11/12/Sisyphus</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/music/2019/11/12/Sisyphus.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Body Memory&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I remember looking through the cold, empty room. Posters plastered the walls, and stickers lined the desks. I scanned through documents and browsed through files, looking for anything of interest on the events that transpired before my arrival. Amongst the mess, I found packets of macaroni and cheese, a pair of panties, and signs of a herculean effort to keep a college radio station running to the best of its ability. There was a constant effort to keep the dying art of radio alive, and eventually it all came crashing down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Paradisia&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With most of the radio station’s key members gone, I eventually came to the realization that if I wanted to do something, I could just do it. I needn’t ask for permission, and provided that I wasn’t breaking any major rules, the absent Program Director wouldn’t say anything. So I spent most of my waking free time at the station. I would do homework there, sit in on people’s shifts, and go on air for eleven to fifteen hours a week. As a consequence of being there so much, I became close to many of the people there and encouraged them to spend their time there as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Claimstaker&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My efforts did not go unnoticed. At the beginning of my second semester, the interim general manager encouraged me to apply for the Program Director position, which unbeknownst to me, was combined with the Station Manager role. I applied, interviewed, and got the position over the person who I assumed was more qualified. That person convinced me my apprehensions and insecurities about my own qualifications were correct, and I stepped down and took a role as their assistant. That was a very &lt;em&gt;Victor I&lt;/em&gt; move of me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Tabula Rasa&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, a certain person talked about reviving a historied station publication, you know the one. It seemed like a good enough idea; what better way to promote the station and show the university we existed? So we worked together to get things started. Eventually, I took it upon myself to work on the editing and layouts, as I had some experience with web development and there is some overlap in the skills necessary. I didn’t have much to go off of: the style guide binder mysteriously disappeared one day, leaving me with a single copy of the previous edition of the publication. All I could do was press on, and keep working as best I could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Loss&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it came time to hire a new General Manager, I was there at the interview. When told there was one candidate, you can imagine how frustrated I was with the inevitability; the university had chosen, and the student staff was there to have the illusion of agency. Even so, I barraged the candidate with questions, trying to figure out exactly what the outlook of the future would be. When I asked why there was only one candidate, I came to my conclusion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;Sue Me&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve never burned out harder than in my second semester as “Assistant Program Director.” Putting all of my free time into the station for so long was not healthy, and the one I was assisting was not doing their job. So I went to the recently hired General Manager and told them that I could not keep things up. And then I told them again: something needed to be done. After the third time, I sat down for an hour and told them I was at the end of what I could handle. The answer was the same as the first two: put up with things for now, and eventually, it will get better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did not take their advice. I was exhausted, at the end of my capacity. So I went to the Senate, the meeting of directors. At the end of that meeting, I announced that I felt as though I was doing more than I could keep up with, and if things did not get better in a month I would resign. The meeting was concluded, the Program Director wept, the boulder cracked.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;center&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;i&gt;The Gate&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I knew what I had done, and meant what it meant for my future. Things were better for a while, at least until it came to hire the new Program Director. When I found out that the current one was on the hiring board, I knew my time pushing that accursed boulder would be coming to an end. My hiring was blocked by one vote. When offered the role of assistant again, you can imagine what went through my head. At least I can be proud of the work I did when I had the chance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III - II</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here Body Memory I remember looking through the cold, empty room. Posters plastered the walls, and stickers lined the desks. I scanned through documents and browsed through files, looking for anything of interest on the events that transpired before my arrival. Amongst the mess, I found packets of macaroni and cheese, a pair of panties, and signs of a herculean effort to keep a college radio station running to the best of its ability. There was a constant effort to keep the dying art of radio alive, and eventually it all came crashing down.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/sisyphus.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/sisyphus.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On Vestoj</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/fashion/2019/11/12/On-Vestoj.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On Vestoj" /><published>2019-11-12T04:50:37-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:50:37-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/fashion/2019/11/12/On-Vestoj</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/fashion/2019/11/12/On-Vestoj.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To write creative nonfiction is to let yourself be vulnerable. You lay bare scars that are otherwise invisible, bring out painful memories that would rather be forgotten. Fashion, conversely, focuses on exclusivity and subtly. Fashion exists to hide and act while communicating silently, if at all. As such, finding creative nonfiction on the topic of fashion is nontrivial, and I spent a lot of time searching until I found myself on the homepage of &lt;em&gt;Vestoj.com&lt;/em&gt;. The design stood out to me from traditional fashion related websites: it had a simple, ad-free layout. There was a large focus on the text with sparse yet impactful photography, and every article had a diverse set of sources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After reading the article &lt;em&gt;Beggars And Choosers&lt;/em&gt; by Johannes Lenhard, I was hooked. Lenhard wasn’t just talking about clothes or runway shows. He wrote about poverty, and psychology, and how they could be viewed under the lens of fashion. It’s a rare thing to have a conversation about, and Vestoj housed a goldmine of articles just like it. I wasn’t seeing random people talk about dressing for dates, or the new streetwear “label” (five graphic t-shirts) they were creating. I was seeing the connection between fashion and everyday life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I’m explaining it in the most dramatic way possible, if only to mirror the feeling I was overcome with upon my discovery. As soon as the eighth issue, &lt;em&gt;On Authenticity&lt;/em&gt;, was released, I paid $30 for a copy and read it cover to cover.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Immediately, the essay &lt;em&gt;Acting As If&lt;/em&gt; by Michelle Millar Fisher jumped out at me. It details the link between wearing counterfeit clothing and feeling fake or inauthentic. Beyond that, those emotions influenced the actions of the wearers to be more dishonest, as well as perceiving others as more dishonest. That observation can be extended to individual thoughts and actions of a person; to believe you are something and act like it is to be that thing. This is the basis for cognitive behavioral therapy, which I eventually came to use a great deal to become free of my perceived self.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That same week, I hosted a “No Limits” radio station (A four hour segment of whatever audio content you could dream of), and read the article &lt;em&gt;The Making of a Star&lt;/em&gt; by Philippa Snow, another impactful essay on performativity, live on air while Aphex Twin played in the background. I wanted everyone to hear what these people had to say.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vestoj remains an important part of my life, enough to have a special place in this journal. Nearly everything I write and design, from print to website, is inspired by it. It’s fueled my interest in fashion and society, and even my own writing. I’m grateful to the London College of Fashion for funding it, and for Anja Aronowsky Cronberg for their founding and editing contributions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Vestoj is a forum where academia, the museum world and the fashion industry can work together and with active communication. We write about the cultural phenomenon that is fashion in a manner that opens up for dialogue between theory and practice in order to raise awareness for fashion as a cultural phenomena and field of research and cultivate an even greater understanding for the discipline. Vestoj will exist outside of seasonally-based trends and news-focused articles. Instead we aim to encourage and champion the critical and independent voice within fashion as well as absolute creative freedom. In order to ensure that we remain free in thought and action Vestoj will have no advertising. Vestoj focuses solely on sartorial matters, bringing together academia and industry in a bid to combine academic theory, critical thinking and a bit of good old fashioned glamour.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III - II</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here To write creative nonfiction is to let yourself be vulnerable. You lay bare scars that are otherwise invisible, bring out painful memories that would rather be forgotten. Fashion, conversely, focuses on exclusivity and subtly. Fashion exists to hide and act while communicating silently, if at all. As such, finding creative nonfiction on the topic of fashion is nontrivial, and I spent a lot of time searching until I found myself on the homepage of Vestoj.com. The design stood out to me from traditional fashion related websites: it had a simple, ad-free layout. There was a large focus on the text with sparse yet impactful photography, and every article had a diverse set of sources.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/vestoj.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/vestoj.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Vomit</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Vomit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Vomit" /><published>2019-11-12T04:50:34-05:00</published><updated>2019-11-12T04:50:34-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Vomit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/11/12/Vomit.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/malocclusion&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In a moment I was awake, stomach-churning and head drooping. Knowing what was coming, I frantically felt around for the phone remote in the half-lit intensive care unit. Then it came: blood. So much blood. Leaking through the gaps in my bound together teeth, filling the cold room with a vaguely metallic stench. I could do nothing but lurch and heave as it fell onto my hospital blanket. There was no chance to reach for the suction tube on my left; I gripped tightly to the rails of the hospital bed every time my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; convulsed and ejected blood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!--more--&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finally, two nurses rushed in to assist me, using the suction tube to suck up the blood and vomit into the half-filled jar behind me. With moist eyes, I laid back, waiting for the morphine and anti-nausea medication to hit the bloodstream. The nurses changed my sheets, my mother came back from the bathroom, and I fell asleep out of exhaustion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first time I looked at my face in the mirror after my double &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; surgery, I could only think of how big a mistake I made. My face blew up like a balloon, and underneath my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt; was a sack of meat the size of an orange. Was this the new face I was promised after all these years? After all this pain? Of course not, but I was hopped up on too many drugs and barely enough sleep to make that mental connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eventually, a wheelchair came to pick me up and relocate me to a normal hospital room. After another day of taking pain and nausea meds and drinking soup stock to keep me alive, I was wheeled out of the hospital. I would go on to vomit again a week later, though this time I was left on my own to clear out everything from my mouth. The things I do for my &lt;em&gt;jaw&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III - II</name></author><summary type="html">This essay was published in Malocclusion: A Post-Bimaxillary Osteotomy Nonfiction Journal, which can be found here In a moment I was awake, stomach-churning and head drooping. Knowing what was coming, I frantically felt around for the phone remote in the half-lit intensive care unit. Then it came: blood. So much blood. Leaking through the gaps in my bound together teeth, filling the cold room with a vaguely metallic stench. I could do nothing but lurch and heave as it fell onto my hospital blanket. There was no chance to reach for the suction tube on my left; I gripped tightly to the rails of the hospital bed every time my jaw convulsed and ejected blood.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/vomit.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/vomit.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">On U92 &amp;amp; The Slow Death of College Radio</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/music/nonfiction/2019/09/03/On-U92-&-the-Slow-Death-of-College-Radio.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="On U92 &amp; The Slow Death of College Radio" /><published>2019-09-03T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-09-03T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/music/nonfiction/2019/09/03/On-U92-&amp;-the-Slow-Death-of-College-Radio</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/music/nonfiction/2019/09/03/On-U92-&amp;-the-Slow-Death-of-College-Radio.html">&lt;p&gt;Written somewhere on the walls of U92’s DJ staff area is the phrase &lt;em&gt;“College radio is dying, friends are forever.”&lt;/em&gt; While I regret to quote the person that uttered it, it remains an unfortunate reality that those in positions of power must confront. WWVU-FM is not an exception. Over one and a half years I associated myself with the station, I searched for a solution. There isn’t one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is in my estimation that U92 will either be completely shut down or morphed into something unrecognizable in 5 years. This estimation can be increased or decreased by the student staff in power, but the result is inevitable. The wants of the student staff have been and will continue to be at odds with the wants of the university. I’ve experienced this personally during the time I spent “acting” as Program Director, and despite my best efforts I failed to provide so much as a band-aide. Looking at the past, this is nothing new. In the pre-strike era, the station was better staffed with more people that cared, yet still, there was no solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is the university-student staff struggle? Essentially, college radio is characterized by two axes. The vertical axis represents the academic focus of the station, and the horizontal axis represents the social focus of the station. One thing to note is that this model is through the lens of the music staff and thus has its own set of flaws.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://localhost:4000//writing/assets/img/college-radio-chart.svg&quot; alt=&quot;The College Radio Chart&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main focus in this model is professionalism vs casualism, and it’s the main source of struggle and conflict in many college radio stations. Become too professional, and the passion of the students will be drained, and the staff will leave. The station becomes too corporate, and the spirit of college radio effectively dies. Become too casual, and the station loses university support, which means no funding and no space to operate, eventually causing a closure. This axis is constantly in a state of flux: the university is pulling college radio to the top right (more professional, and widely accessible), and the student staff is pulling things to the bottom left (More artful and niche). If either side gains too much control, the station axed. Of course, things can drift to the top left or bottom right, however they aren’t common cases and I won’t be focusing on them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So where does U92 stand right now? According to my investigation, the station has been quickly sliding to the top right due to a chain of events started by the loss of Alex G. in 2015. His death left the station in a state of disarray. The second event was the station-wide strike that occurred in 2017. Due to the negligence of the university and Title IX, the station was again sent into disarray, and many talented and passionate student staff members disassociated with the station (Though it can be argued that this was the best outcome, lest the station was shut down). The next event lies in the future: the DA-U92 Merger. While they have been technically merged for some years now, the location change threatens the independence and autonomy of U92. Unfortunately, if the merge doesn’t happen, the university could very well throw in the towel and shut things down for good. It’s an unwinnable situation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this case, the details and particularities of the situation do not matter. There’s nothing that the student staff or broadcast advisor can reasonably do about it. This doesn’t however, mean you shouldn’t do anything. For those reading this that are still associated with the station, I offer two pieces of advice. Firstly, enjoy it while you can. Use the resources at the station to be creative to your fullest potential; they won’t last forever. Secondly, focus on the local community. If there’s any way to have an impact outside of the university, it’s them. Promote local acts, host local events, and shows. They are the true heart of U92, and your impact will live on with them no matter what.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III</name></author><summary type="html">Written somewhere on the walls of U92’s DJ staff area is the phrase “College radio is dying, friends are forever.” While I regret to quote the person that uttered it, it remains an unfortunate reality that those in positions of power must confront. WWVU-FM is not an exception. Over one and a half years I associated myself with the station, I searched for a solution. There isn’t one.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/u92death.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/u92death.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Universal Principles of Design for Programmers: Part 1</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/tech/2019/08/28/Universal-Principles-of-Design-for-Programmers-Part-1.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Universal Principles of Design for Programmers: Part 1" /><published>2019-08-28T00:50:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-28T00:50:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/tech/2019/08/28/Universal-Principles-of-Design-for-Programmers-Part-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/tech/2019/08/28/Universal-Principles-of-Design-for-Programmers-Part-1.html">&lt;p&gt;During my third year of studying Computer Science, I wanted to vary up my schedule and add an English class to mix things up. I ended up taking Multimedia Writing, an upper-level English class intended for writers and designers. Despite being unnecessary for my degree, that class ended up being an incredibly valuable learning experience for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;table-of-contents&quot;&gt;Table Of Contents&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#what&quot;&gt;What are Universal Principles of Design?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#80/20&quot;&gt;80/20 Rule&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Aesthetic-Usability&quot;&gt;Aesthetic-Usability Effect&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Affordance&quot;&gt;Affordance&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Archetypes&quot;&gt;Archetypes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Chunking&quot;&gt;Chunking&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Closure&quot;&gt;Closure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#Conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-what-are-universal-principles-of-design-&quot;&gt;🤷‍ What Are “Universal Principles of Design?” &lt;a name=&quot;what&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, &lt;strong&gt;universal principles of design&lt;/strong&gt; are design principles that can be applied to many different disciplines. You could be organizing your house, making a poster, or even writing an operating system and use the same principles for all three. In this series, I’ll be referencing the book &lt;em&gt;Universal Principles of Design&lt;/em&gt; by &lt;em&gt;William Lidwell&lt;/em&gt;, an invaluable reference for design of any kind. In this case, however, I’ll be taking specific ones and explaining how they relate to programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-8020-rule-&quot;&gt;📏 80/20 Rule &lt;a name=&quot;80/20&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A high percentage of effects in any large system are caused by a low percentage of variables.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80% of effort in a project is in the last 20% of work&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80% of bugs are caused by 20% of the program&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;80% of application usage involves 20% of the functions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’ve ever worked on a large application of any kind, you’ve probably figured out by now that most users will never use every single feature. It’s more likely the same handful of functions are used all the time, while the edge-case functions are rarely used, if at all. That’s not to say that handling edge cases isn’t important, but you can’t let the scope of your application get out of control when working towards strict deadlines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-aesthetic-usability-effect&quot;&gt;🖼 Aesthetic-Usability Effect&lt;a name=&quot;Aesthetic-Usability&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Aesthetic designs are perceived as easier to use than less-aesthetic designs.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ah yes, the dreaded programmer UI. At some point or another, we’ve all whipped up a quick GUI to test out the functionality of what we’re working on. Sadly, that’s not good enough when it comes to the final product. It doesn’t matter how bug-free or perfect a piece of software is; if it’s ugly, it’s going to be used less. A designer can be just as important to a programmer when it comes to the success of your application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-affordance&quot;&gt;🚪 Affordance&lt;a name=&quot;Affordance&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A property in which the physical characteristics of an object or environment influence its function.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This one goes out to all the people who couldn’t stop thinking about doors after reading &lt;em&gt;The Design of Everyday Things&lt;/em&gt;. Things users interact with should make sense. A link should look like a link. A button should look like a button. Attention to detail is important, and the less time a user spends thinking about your design, the less you need to explain it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-archetypes&quot;&gt;💾 Archetypes&lt;a name=&quot;Archetypes&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Universal patterns of theme and form resulting from innate biases or dispositions.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Naming remains an incredibly important part of programming. So much so that conventions and style guides are written to keep everyone on the same page. You can also use archetypes to make complex functions easier to understand in code. For example: say you have a program that stores a list of students, and a function that removes students with a GPA under 2.0. Naming your function &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;removeStudents()&lt;/code&gt; is too ambiguous. You could try something longer such as &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;removeStudentsUnderGPALimit()&lt;/code&gt;, which is unambiguous, but that reduces readability. A good solution could be &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;expellForGPA()&lt;/code&gt;, as expelling is a real-world pattern that most people will be familiar with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-chunking&quot;&gt;🎒 Chunking&lt;a name=&quot;Chunking&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A technique of combining many units of information into a limited number of units or chunks, so that the information is easier to process and remember.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Information overload can be a big issue when displaying necessary data to both users and collaborators. A classic example I see is when beginners first learn about commenting code and then proceed to fill the beginning of every file with a large multi-line comment explaining the purpose of every object, variable, and function. Large walls of text often end up being ignored, so break up your comments when you can.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-closure&quot;&gt;🧩 Closure&lt;a name=&quot;Closure&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;A tendency to perceive a set of individual elements as a single, recognizable pattern, rather than multiple, individual elements.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a different definition of closure than the programming one you’re probably used to seeing. A closure in design refers to how our brains naturally look for patterns. In UI, you can leverage this to simplify the amount of information displayed on the screen (for both performance and readability’s sake). In code, you can use the thought process behind this principle to make things more readable. Take JavaScript’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Array.prototype.map()&lt;/code&gt; for example.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;for&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;length&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;++&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
  &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;]&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While iterating through arrays is trivial, it still takes mental overhead when reading to ensure that everything is behaving as expected. We can simplify this using &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Array.prototype.map()&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;language-javascript highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;[&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;1&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;3&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;];&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;kd&quot;&gt;let&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;doubledList&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;list&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;.&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;map&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nx&quot;&gt;item&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;2&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;);&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you learn how this pattern works, your mind will subconsciously tell you “an action is being taken on every item in this list.” Under the hood, it might just be a for loop, but we don’t have to think about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;-conclusion&quot;&gt;🙇‍ Conclusion&lt;a name=&quot;Conclusion&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This concludes this part of &lt;em&gt;Universal Principles of Design for Programmers&lt;/em&gt;! Hopefully these principles made you think about what design can do for you. More principles to come!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III</name></author><summary type="html">During my third year of studying Computer Science, I wanted to vary up my schedule and add an English class to mix things up. I ended up taking Multimedia Writing, an upper-level English class intended for writers and designers. Despite being unnecessary for my degree, that class ended up being an incredibly valuable learning experience for me.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/UPDFP_1.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/UPDFP_1.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Exploring Microgenres: Digital Hardcore</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/music/2019/08/21/Expoloring-Microgenres-Digital-Hardcore.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Exploring Microgenres: Digital Hardcore" /><published>2019-08-21T00:49:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-08-21T00:49:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/music/2019/08/21/Expoloring-Microgenres-Digital-Hardcore</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/music/2019/08/21/Expoloring-Microgenres-Digital-Hardcore.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This article was originally published for the Fall 2019 edition of WIRELESS, which can be found &lt;a href=&quot;https://victorjperez.github.io/wireless&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It can be argued that we are currently living in the era most accessible for electronic music. Anyone with access to a computer has an incredibly wide selection of free and paid digital audio workstations, alongside a plethora of other music production tools. With this has come an explosion of hard-to-categorize music that transcends traditional genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With all that being said, It’s not enough to just say an artist produces “electronic” music. Even subgenres like techno and jungle have loose definitions that are often subverted by masters of the craft. Nonetheless, music fans and pundits insist on creating very specific categorizations, and electronic music is often broken down into what is essentially microgenres. In this
scenario we’ll be looking specifically at Digital Hardcore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The term digital hardcore was coined in the 1992 by Alec Empire of Atari Teenage Riot, the pioneer of the genre. He went on to form the label Digital Hardcore Records, which specialized in artists of the genre. Unfortunately the scene reamains small, much like other electronic microgenres such as witch house or vaporwave.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So what exactly is Digital Hardcore? For the most part, it can be considered a fusion of many different genres: techno, noise, drum and bass, breakbeat and hardcore punk. The end result is music that is especially fast, abrasive and angry. Occasionally it will make use of “traditional” punk instruments such as electric guitars , alongside synthesizers and drum machines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lyrically, there isn’t as clear of a theme in the genre. From a historical point of view, bands such as Alec Empire used many left-wing or anarchist ideals in their lyrics. While occasionally these will come up in other artist’s music, it’s certainly a less prominent feature of the genre. Despite losing the theme the genre used to have, the vocals are still typically screamed and shouted, with a powerful manic energy unmatched in other electronic genres.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though I have a fairly high interest in electronic music, the genre managed to fly under my radar. That is, until the band Machine Girl brought this style to my attention with their release &lt;em&gt;…Because I’m Young Arrogant and Hate Everything You Stand For&lt;/em&gt; (their 2018 release &lt;em&gt;The Ugly Art&lt;/em&gt; also made our top 92 list). Since them, I’ve come to find that few artists produce the very specific style that was popularized by Digital Hardcore Records these days. It lives on through its influence above all else.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t know where to start with digital hardcore? Listen to &lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/playlist/7w1RL1yFhPolVdx2GpgBrf?si=KIBUaFAZTvyB09Vm9rFVhg&quot;&gt;this&lt;/a&gt; playlist filled with staple creators of the genre, as well as artists heavily influenced by it.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III</name></author><summary type="html">This article was originally published for the Fall 2019 edition of WIRELESS, which can be found here</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/wireless.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/wireless.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry><entry><title type="html">Keep Smoking, I Still Love You</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/04/22/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Keep Smoking, I Still Love You" /><published>2019-04-22T06:42:34-04:00</published><updated>2019-04-22T06:42:34-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/04/22/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/writing/nonfiction/2019/04/22/Keep-Smoking-I-Still-Love-You.html">&lt;p&gt;For as long as I can remember, I’ve found the smell of cigarettes comforting. In the far reaches of my memory are scenes of my grandfather’s kitchen, where I sat waiting for him while he was out on the porch. The door opens as someone enters the house, and I catch the ethereal scent of cigarette smoke as the door quickly closes behind them. I don’t have a particularly close connection to my grandfather, or even his house for that matter. Nonetheless, any time I notice the smell, it brings a wave of comfort and pleasant feelings.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even after four years, I remain surprised at the amount of people who smoke cigarettes in this town. Back at home, it was a rarity to see someone smoke unless you went into the city. I’ve lost count of the people I know in Morgantown who smoke.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of cigarettes I’ve smoked remains in the single digits, and will probably stay that way for the rest of my lifetime. Kate was the first person I smoked with. During parties we would occasionally both become overwhelmed, and relax on the porch together. For whatever reason, she only smokes when she drinks, and we were able to enjoy the quiet company of each other and the cool midnight air. I adore thinking of those moments, each tied together by the memory of her lit cigarette. Eventually one day the siren smell of her clove cigarette hit me, and I innocently requested a puff. The flavor of clove jumped out on me, and lingered on my lips as it passed it to hers. I can’t recall anything else about that day: just her and I, passing that single black cigarette back and forth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve grown to find Morgantown comforting. Previously the aggressiveness of this town frightened me, but those around me have helped me enjoy my presence here. There are times I think about my fear of leaving and wonder if I’ve been conditioned to love this town.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last time I smoked was with Kate. We were passing each other a clove cigarette, from a pack I bought for her. There was a sense of guilt radiating from her about the passing on of her habit. After a short while of her mincing words, I decided to stop before it truly did become a habit. That day is burned into my memory: she was wearing a long dress with flowers, and we sat together on the steps behind the college radio station. I didn’t sleep well that night, the pain of hurting each other kept me awake. I still miss the intimacy of sharing cigarettes with her on porches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I left Morgantown, I would be leaving Kate behind. My head grows light and my eyes moisten when I think about this. She’s been very upfront about wanting me to leave for a better life, but I can feel the hesitation. Would it be that bad to stay?&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Victor J Perez III</name></author><summary type="html">For as long as I can remember, I’ve found the smell of cigarettes comforting. In the far reaches of my memory are scenes of my grandfather’s kitchen, where I sat waiting for him while he was out on the porch. The door opens as someone enters the house, and I catch the ethereal scent of cigarette smoke as the door quickly closes behind them. I don’t have a particularly close connection to my grandfather, or even his house for that matter. Nonetheless, any time I notice the smell, it brings a wave of comfort and pleasant feelings.</summary><media:thumbnail xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/porch.png" /><media:content medium="image" url="http://localhost:4000/writing/porch.png" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" /></entry></feed>